<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<!--
    Copyright 2010-2011 The MyBatis Team

    Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.
-->

<!--
    version: $Id$
-->
<chapter id="introduction">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <section id="introduction.why-mybatis-guice">
        <title>Why mybatis-guice - Motivation</title>
        <para>
            In our daily work we've been strongly using both
            <ulink url="http://www.mybatis.org/">MyBatis Sql Mapper</ulink> and
            <ulink url="http://code.google.com/p/google-guice/">Google Guice</ulink>
            frameworks and once noticed we'd been continuosly repeating the same
            code snippets in different projects, according to the DRY
            <emphasis>don't repeat yourself</emphasis> principle, we started
            realizing something that alleviate us the task to create our stuff.
        </para>
        <para>
            Indeed, this small library intends to create the missing perfect glue
            between the two popular frameworks, reducing the boilerplate and
            redundant code that users have to write to configure and use MyBatis
            into a Google Guice context.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="introduction.story">
        <title>A little bit of history</title>
        <para>
            The mybatis-guice library was born during the Christmas' vacation in
            the far December 2009, with the name of <ulink url="http://www.99soft.org/projects/ibaguice/1.0">iBaGuice</ulink>
            on Google Code, created and maintained by the <ulink url="http://www.99soft.org/">99soft.org</ulink>
            folks Marco Speranza and Simone Tripodi.
        </para>
        <para>
            Since the two communities where strictly collaborating, Clinton Begin,
            the creator of the MyBatis project, invited Simone Tripodi to join the
            MyBatis team, bringing with him the <emphasis>iBaGuice</emphasis>
            code base to become an official MyBatis subproject.
        </para>
        <para>
            By that day, the mybatis-guice project is maintained by the MyBatis.org
            team.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="introduction.requirements">
        <title>Requirements</title>
        <para>
            Before starting reading the manual, it is very important you're
            familiar with both MyBatis and Google Guice framework and therminology.
        </para>
        <para>
            Like MyBatis and Google Guice, mybatis-guice requires Java 5 or higher.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="introduction.acks">
        <title>Acknowledgements</title>
        <para>
            A special thanks goes to all the special people who made the Google Guice
            integration a reality, above all Clinton Begin, who strongly believed
            on that MyBatis sub-project, and Marco Speranza, without him that
            project wouldn't exist.
        </para>
        <para>
            Special acknowledgments go to Stephen Friedrich for providing an amazing patch,
            Poitras Christian who made the XML module a reality and Marzia Forli for the JRS330 feedbacks.
        </para>
    </section>

</chapter>
